Jonathan Camilo Narvaez Martinez

Software Engineer, Frontend Developer, ReactJS.

(+57) 317 8559 796
Time zone: Bogotá, Colombia
joncyy 19@hotmail.com
jonxthxn1911@gmail.com
https://github.com/Naramatsu
https://curriculum-jcnm.vercel.app

Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience developing web applications using ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3 and SASS. Involved in building high scalable frontend components and backend APIs standardization to speed up programming. Very interested in working under organized software development methodologies, also in contributing to find clean and optime solutions to facilitate and expedite the maintainability and development of world-class software. In love with ReactJS on Frontend and NodeJS on Backend. In addition I've the ability to lead and perform teamwork; a person qualified to follow and receive orders of high responsibilities. I am ready to apply the knowledge learned and willing to continue with the intellectual formation. I adapt easily to different environments.

EXPERIENCE

Tech Mahindra, ReactJS Web UI Developer (Cartagena, Colombia) — Feb 2023 - Apr 2024

- Colpatria bank application Creation of an application in ReactJS + Redux and others, conformed by a group of 2 QA testers, 2 business analysts, 1 agile facilitator, 4 backend developers and 4 frontend developers, each one was in charge of features created in the backlog according to the Product Owner projections.
 - Develop reusable and scalable components.
 - Maintaining components, applications and microservices in order for the user has a very good user experience.
 - Planning and estimation tasks.
 - Unit testing with Jest of the different frontend application elements like components, reducers, hooks and util functions.
 - o Bitbucket.
 - Play under SCRUM methodology.
- Techs
 - o HTML5
 - o CSS3
 - Javascript
 - ReactJs
 - React hooks
 - ES6
 - o Git
 - Bitbucket
 - Redux
 - Redux-thunk
 - styled-components

- Jira
- Jest
- o Api REST
- Mockups

Freelance Frontend Developer UI/UX Designer (Cartagena, Colombia) — Oct 2021 - current — (Personal Projects)

- Kromac-UI (Style framework) is a 100% responsive style framework that seeks to facilitate the development and implementation of eye-catching components with modern styles to web applications.
 - Develop reusable and scalable components which are very easy to implement in an external react project.
 - Design of the components.
 - o Maintain the framework.
 - Adding new Features.
 - o Fixing bugs.
- Mockups for a Store application.
 - Design a minimalistic web application with easy access to components
 - o Create style components to reuse, creating variants, etc.
- Techs
 - o HTML5
 - o CSS3
 - Javascript
 - ReactJs
 - React hooks
 - SASS
 - ES6
 - o Git
 - o Github
 - Webpack
 - o Figma
 - Jest

EPAM, ReactJS Web UI Developer (Cartagena, Colombia) — May 2022 - Sep 2022

- Growth (Improving and acquiring knowledge) Reinforcing knowledge in ReactJS, React hooks, ReactJs + Typescript, React Native (for android) and NextJS. Learning basic concepts in user interface design with Figma, I worked on personal projects like: OAuth login services with JWT + Google + NodeJS, News application for android devices, Mockups for a Store application.
 - Develop reusable and scalable applications.
 - Using github
- Techs
 - o HTML5
 - o CSS3
 - Javascript
 - ReactJs
 - React hooks

- o SASS
- o ES6
- o Git
- o Github
- Typescript
- React Native
- NextJs
- Figma
- Aws
- Google
- NodeJs

Condor Labs, Full Stack Developer (Cartagena, Colombia) — May 2020 - May 2022

- Education web application Creation of an application in ReactJS + SASS + Redux + NojdeJS + Express + MongoDB + OracleDB + AWS stack, conformed by a group of 3 backend developers and 1 frontend developer, each one was in charge of features created in the backlog according to the Product Owner projections.
 - o Develop reusable and scalable components.
 - Maintaining components, applications and microservices in order for the user has a very good user experience.
 - Standardization, documentation and APIs simplification of the main core components, design systems improving the components reusability.
 - Implementing tools for forms to handle validations in frontend and backend through a JSON schema using React Hook Forms.
 - Planning and estimation tasks to work for a quarter (3 months).
 - Unit testing with Jest of the different frontend application elements like components, reducers, hooks and util functions.
 - Using github
 - Play under SCRUM methodology.
- Techs
 - o HTML5
 - o CSS3
 - Javascript
 - ReactJs
 - React hooks
 - Bootstrap
 - Emerald-UI
 - SASS
 - o ES6
 - o Redux
 - Redux-thunk
 - NodeJs
 - o Express
 - AWS
 - MongoDB
 - Oracle
 - o Redis
 - o Git

- o Github
- Jest
- o Api REST
- o Mockups

Zeus tecnologias, Full Stack Developer (Cartagena, Colombia) — May 2019 - May 2020

- Restaurant Application Maintaining an application in Foxpro, Visual Basic and migrating to ASP .Net, conformed by a group of 3 full stack developers, each one was in charge of features created in the backlog according to the Product Owner projections.
 - Adding new features.
 - Real-time customer support.
 - Standardization and documentation of the main core components, and user manual.
 - Using github
 - Play under SCRUM methodology.
- Techs
 - o HTML5
 - o CSS3
 - Javascript
 - SQL Server
 - C#
 - o ASP.NET
 - Visual Basic
 - o Fox Pro

VISO Infinity Travels, Practitioner (Cartagena, Colombia) — Jan 2019 - May 2019

- Web site and application Creation of the main website of the enterprise, maintaining the content, updating new offerts, conformed by a group of 2 full stack developers, each one was in charge of features created in the backlog.
 - Creation of the website and application.
 - Adding new features.
 - Keep up to date the information..
 - Standardization and documentation of the main core components, and user manual.
 - Using github
 - Play under SCRUM methodology.
- Techs
 - o HTML5
 - o CSS3
 - Javascript
 - JQUERY
 - o MySQL

EDUCATION

Systems Engineering (Cartagena, Colombia) — Jan 2014 - Apr 2020

• Fundacion Universitaria Tecnologico Comfenalco

High school (Turbaco, Colombia) — Dec 2013

• Institucion Educativa Docente de Turbaco

LANGUAGES

Spanish: NativeEnglish: B1

ATTACHMENTS



Pen su nombre la

Institución Educativa Mocente Me Turbaco

Autorizado por la Secretaria de Educación Departamental de Bolíbar según Resolución 0462 del 21 de Diciembre de 2006

Confiere a:

NARVAEZ MARTINEZ JONATHAN CAMILO

Identificado (a) con T.I. 96111910640 de TURBACO

El Titulo de:

Bachiller Académico

Por haber cursado y aprobado los estudios correspondientes al nivel de Educación Media Académica según los planes y programas vigentes.

őr

Secretaria

Curbaco, 4 be Biciembre be 2013

Libro A'. 00/ Folio A'. /36 A' be Registro 063

Dabo en Turbaco, Bolivar el bia 4 bel mes be Diciembre de 2013



Fundación Universitaria TECNOLÓGICO COMFENALCO

Institución Universitaria con Personería Jurídica reconocida mediante resolución 5642 de septiembre 19 de 2006 expedida por el Ministerio de Educación Nacional Código SNIES 3705

En atención que

Hantlian Mamila Marvaez Martinez

C.C. No. 1050970596 de Turbaco

Ha cumplido los requisitos académicos exipidos por la Institución y las disposiciones legales para optar por el titulo de

Ternálogo en Desarrollo de Software

Dado en Cartagena, a los 30 días del mes de septiembre de 2017

Registro en el Folio No. 0014

Diploma No. 18694

Del Libro de Actas No. 00157

Malio Emeral



Fundación Universitaria TECNOLÓGICO COMFENALCO

Con personeria juridica reconocida mediante Resolución 5642 de septiembre 19 de 2006 expedida por el Ministerio de Educación Nacional y NIT 890481183 – 1

Que el código de registro como Institución de Educación Superior ante el Sistema Nacional de Información de la Educación Superior (SNIES) de la Fundación Universitaria Tecnológico Comfenalco es el 3705.

LA COORDINADORA DE ADMISIONES Y REGISTRO

CERTIFICA

Que, JONATHAN CAMILO NARVÁEZ MARTÍNEZ, con documento de identidad No. 1.050.970.596 de Turbaco - Bolívar, es egresado de esta institución del programa de INGENIERÍA DE SISTEMAS, terminó académicamente en el segundo periodo académico de 2018.

Que, para optar por el título de Ingeniería de Sistemas, de acuerdo a lo establecido en el Reglamento Estudiantil, debe cumplir con todos los requisitos de graduación exigidos por la Institución, y lo dispuesto en el Artículo No. 82 "El egresado que transcurridos cuatro periodos académicos desde la culminación del plan de estudios del programa del cual egresa sin optar por su graduación. Deberá cumplir con los requisitos de evaluación, actualización o nivelación establecidos por la respectiva Decanatura".

NINGUNA ANOTACIÓN POSTERIOR TIENE VALIDEZ

Se expide a solicitud del interesado a los treinta y un (31) días del mes enero de 2020.



Los certificados que presenten enmendaduras no tendrán validez NOTA: Autenticaciones Notaria Tercera Certificado sellado con sello seco. Elaborado por E.M.





Certifica que:

JONATHAN NARVAEZ MARTINEZ

Asistió al Taller de Formación en Estrategias Pedagógicas Básicas para los Monitores del Proyecto de Permanencia 2-2017 «PLAN PADRINO ACADÉMICO», con una intensidad de ocho (8) horas.

Dado en Cartagena de Indias D.T y C. seis (6) días del mes de Septiembre de 2017

Ivan Caraptón Gómez Coordinador Permanencia Académica Enyel Manyoma Ledesma Directora de pedagogia